## **Cheng Liu**

Software Engineer, System & Infrastructure

## Summary

I am a software engineer at Google Search Infrastructure.

With both academia research background and industry working experience, I focus on designing and developing (distributed) systems that can handle large scale of data.

Big fan of distributed system, consensus algorithm, NoSQL database and BigData framework.

## Experience

#### **Software Engineer III at Google**

October 2016 - Present

Crawl and Indexing, build large scale system and advanced algorithm to optimize crawl decision.

#### **Software Engineer II at Google**

October 2015 - September 2016 (1 year)

Crawl and Indexing, build large scale system and advanced algorithm to optimize crawl decision.

#### Software Engineer at LinkedIn

March 2015 - October 2015 (8 months)

Data Infrastructure

Espresso Storage Team

Espresso is the most popular NoSQL database @ Linkedin, used by almost every important service.

http://data.linkedin.com/projects/espresso

http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2465298

http://www.slideshare.net/amywtang/li-espresso-sigmodtalk

#### Research Assistant at Columbia University in the City of New York

January 2014 - February 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Working on Distributed System to provide general application replication technology under the supervision of Prof. Junfeng Yang.

Related Keyword: Deterministic Multithread Technology, Paxos Protocol, Asynchronous network communication, Integration Test.

#### Research Assistant at Tsinghua University

June 2012 - July 2013 (1 year 2 months)

Worked in Network Security Lab, focusing on applying "Sampling Smoothed Analysis" to different DFA-like structure in network packets processing, also investigated SDN.

#### **Radio Network Tools Team Intern at Ericsson**

July 2012 - October 2012 (4 months)

•Contributed in Large 2G/3G/LTE communication data visualization and management software system.

## Education

## **Tsinghua University**

Bachelor's degree, Automation, 2008 - 2013

Activities and Societies: Student Union Of Tsinghua Univ, Chorus team Of Tsinghua Univ, 4th Global

Tsinghua Berkeley Entrepreneur project member

Columbia University - Fu Foundation School of Engineering and Applied Science

Master, Computer Science, 2013 - 2014

## Honors and Awards

Example of Tsinghua University Outstanding Student Leaders in 2010, MSRA Fellowship of Computer Science Department in Columbia University

# **Cheng Liu**

Software Engineer, System & Infrastructure



Contact Cheng on LinkedIn